Brown, Fred R.; Papers mss004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Fred R. Brown Papers
1882-1966
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss004
8 cubic ft.
Methodist missionary and science teacher in the Kiansi Province of China from 1910 to 1931. He and his wife, a fellow missionary, later settled in DeWitt, New York.
Biographical Sketch
Fred R. Brown, the son of Reverend and Mrs. Edgar H. Brown, was born in Rensselaer, New York, on May 19, 1888. In 1906, Brown graduated from Albany High School. He earned his Bachelor of Arts degree, magna cum laude, in 1910 from Syracuse University where he had studied biology, chemistry, and medicine. In 1916 he received a master's degree in religious education from the School of Education of Boston University. After future study at Syracuse University in 1931-1932 he completed the requirements of the New York State Department of Education for the provisional professional certificate in teaching.
In 1910 Brown was ordained in the Methodist Episcopal Church. He was sent by the Board of Foreign Missions to Nanchang, China. He served as Head of the Natural Science Department at the William Nast College, Kiukiang, from 1910 to 1916; from 1917 to 1931 he taught at Nanchang Academy and also served as Acting Principal (1918-1919) and Head of the Department of Natural Science (1927-1931). From 1918 to 1924 he was Superintendent of Primary Schools in Nanchang, Kan River, and Kienchang districts.
Brown returned to the United States in 1931. He was Head of the Department of Science and Mathematics at Pebble Hill School in Dewitt, New York, and then moved to Troy. In 1938 he became pastor of the Levings Methodist Church and also taught an orientation course in natural science at Russell Sage College.
From 1942 into 1958 Mr. Brown served churches in Richmondville, Warnerville, Fonda, Fultonville, Cambridge, White Creek, Clarksville, and Reidsville. In May 1958 he became pastor of St. James Methodist Church, Cohoes, and retired in May 1961.
He was appointed pastor emeritus of Pine Grove Methodist Church of Colonie where he served as the missions commission head and was in charge of the men's Bible class. He was head of the historical committee and retired ministers' group of the Troy Methodist Conference.
Fred R. Brown married Clella Ernestine McDonnell at Nanking, China, on December 8, 1914. Their first son, Fred R. Brown Jr., was born in 1916 and died in 1920. A daughter, Hester, was born in 1918, and a son, Charles, in 1921.
The Reverend Mr. Brown died on December 31, 1966, at the age of 78.
Scope and Contents
The concentration of materials in this Collection is on the period of 1910 to 1931 when Fred R. Brown and his wife, Clella Ernestine McDonnell, served in the Methodist mission in Nanchang, China. The most valuable sources of information are the "Letters home", which contain detailed descriptions of personal activities, travel, weather, and political observations.
The Browns were analytical and observant. They studied the geography of the Kan River District and Kiangsi Province; clan customs, literacy, and superstitions of the people; political conditions; military activities. Their reports and letters are of interest in learning about a time of change in China; their first-hand accounts of the activities of the Nationalist Armies in 1926-1927 are of particular importance to researchers in this period.
Religious instruction and the work of missionary churches is covered in notes on Bible study; dramatic exercises and other teaching materials; reports of church conferences; survey articles.
The ministerial work of Fred Brown upon his return to the United States is covered in the collection of church notices, order of service, notes on specific religious topics, and in the extensive collection of "Sermon Notes" (for the period 1937 to 1961). The material on the Troy Conference of the Methodist Church includes published reports, Brown's notes, and his work on local parish histories.
The items on Clella Ernestine McDonnell (Mrs. Fred R. Brown) deal primarily with her family history, kindergarten instruction, and student papers (many of these are stories based on her experiences in China).
The large collection of photographs supplement the descriptions given in letters and reports. In addition to photographs of China and other locales, there are many family items.
Maps, books, and pamphlets in Chinese, and writings by others on a range of topics, supplement the items produced by Fred and Clella Brown.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1882-1932
Series 2: Diaries and Notebooks, 1908-1946
Series 3: Financial Records, 1923-1963
Series 4: Correspondence, 1910-1965
Series 5: China and the Far East, 1926-1927
Series 6: Kan River District, 1922
Series 7: Kiangsi Province, 1920-1924
Series 8: Kienchang and Nanchang districts, 1922
Series 9: Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang Mission, 1912-1959
Series 10: Teaching at the Nanchang Mission, 1920s
Series 11: University of Amoy, 1931, undated
Series 12: Mission Conferences, 1920-1948
Series 13: Religious Teaching and Preaching in the U.S., 1936-1961
Series 14: Church and Teaching Activities, 1937-1961
Series 15: Troy Conference of the Methodist Board of Missions, 1945-1965
Series 16: Miscellaneous, 1925-1940
Series 17: Clella Ernestine McDonnell (Mrs. Fred R. Brown), 1912-1949
Series 18: Photographs and Maps, 1888-1966
Series 19: Miscellaneous, 1916-1918, undated
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Hester B. Hill, daughter, in 1971, with donations of additional material in 1983.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Rensselaer County, New York; Military and Armed Conflict; China -- Politics and government -- 1912-1949.; China -- Religion -- 20th century.; China -- Description and travel.; England -- Description and travel.; Communism -- China.; Methodist Church -- Missions -- China.; Methodists -- Missionaries.; Brown, Fred R., 1888-1966.; Brown, Clella E. McDonnell.; Brown, Hester.; Gaw, Evaline.; Johnson, William R.; Leese, Holly.
- Biographical Material, 1882-1932; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical material on Fred R. Brown; items relating to his father, Edgar H. Brown; FRB's educational and professional records; documents (wedding certificate, insurances, pension, etc.); newspaper clippings about FRB and his work.
  - Edgar H. Brown (father): Deacon paper, 1882 April 23 (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 1)
  - Edgar H. Brown (father): Elder paper, 1886 April 25 (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 2)
  - Edgar H. Brown (father): Correspondence, greeting cards, tributes upon his death, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 3)
  - Academic records; professional qualifications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 4)
  - Syracuse University, 1910-1965 (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 5)
  - Courses and papers, 1931-1932 (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 6)
  - Employment: resume, letters of recommendation, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 7)
  - Military exemption, 1918 (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 8)
  - Certificate of marriage, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 9)
  - Wedding, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 10)
  - Medical records, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 11)
  - Passports, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 12)
  - Furlough (1931-1932): analysis, freight charges, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 13)
  - Health insurance; life insurance, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 14)
  - Pension; service record, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 15)
  - Will, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 16)
  - Clippings about F. R. Brown and his work, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 17)
  - File numbers and examples of folders, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical Material), Folder 18)
- Diaries and Notebooks, 1908-1946; 2
  Diaries and notebooks of FRB. The diaries contain brief notes about the weather, meals, and activities, covering the years 1917 to 1935. The notebooks cover many topics: financial records, ideas for sermons, class notes, conference reports: they date from 1908 to 1946.
  - Diaries, 1917-1921; 1922-1926 (Box 1 (2-Diaries and Notebooks), Folder 19)
  - Diaries, 1926 July 1-1926 December 31; 1927 January 1-1927 December 31 (Box 1 (2-Diaries and Notebooks), Folder 20)
    also Miscellaneous Notes; 1935 Year Book.
  - Notebooks: Chemistry, 1908 (Box 1 (2-Diaries and Notebooks), Folder 21)
  - Notebooks: Electrical apparatus, 1910; 1922-1923; 1927 October-1929 February; 1931-1942; 1945-1946 (Box 1 (2-Diaries and Notebooks), Folder 21)
- Financial Records, 1923-1963; 3
  Financial records for the years 1923-1963. Cover family accounts and investments, cash and household accounts, auto records, egg production, etc.
  - Cash accounts, 1923 October 1-1925 November 30 (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 22)
  - Family accounts and investments, 1925-1935 (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 23)
  - Household accounts, 1927 Summer (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 24)
  - Household accounts, 1929 August; 1932 (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 25)
  - Financial records, 1940-1948 (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 26)
  - Financial records, 1948-1960 (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 27)
  - Expenses, auto records, egg production, etc, 1958-1963 (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 28)
  - Data needed for judging property, Undated (Box 1 (3-Financial Records), Folder 29)
- Correspondence, 1910-1965; 4
  Correspondence relating to FRB's appointment by the Board of Foreign Missions of the Methodist Episcopal Church; his travels, observations, and work in China; his personal and pastoral activities after returning to United States. Note: Some correspondence is filed with appropriate subject.
  - Correspondence, General, 1910-1913 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, General, 1925-1926 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, General, 1927 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, General, 1928 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, General, 1931-1938 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Letters home, 1910-1911 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    (Extracts: two notebooks).
  - Letters home, 1911 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Letters home, 1912 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Letters home, 1913 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Letters home, 1914 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Letters home, 1915 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Letters home, 1916 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - The Journal of the Brown Family Journey from Shanghai to London, 1924 May-1924 June (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Letters home, 1926 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    (letter of August 29 is on political and military views).
  - Letters home, 1926; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Letters home, 1927 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Letters home, 1927; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Letters home, 1928 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Letters home, 1928; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Letters home, 1929 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Letters home, 1929; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Letters home, 1930 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Letters home, 1930; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Letters home, 1931 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Letters home, 1931; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Letters home, 1932; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Letters, 1933-1934; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Letters, 1935-1936; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Letters, 1937-1938; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Letters, 1939; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Letters, 1940; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Letters, 1941; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Letters, 1942; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Letters, 1943; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Letters, 1944; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Letters, 1945; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Letters, 1946; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Letters, 1947; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Letters, 1948; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Letters, 1949; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Letters, 1950; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Letters, 1951; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Letters, 1952; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Letters, 1953; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Letters, 1954; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Letters, 1955; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Letters, 1956; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Letters, 1957; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Letters, 1958; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Letters, 1959-1960; carbons (Box 2 (4-Correspondence), Folder 50)
  - Correspondence with FRB's family (father, mother, aunt), 1912-1938 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Letters from Rev. Edgar D. Brown, 1947-1953 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Letters from Clella E. McDonnell and Edgar D. Brown, 1914 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Letters from friends to Clella re engagement, 1914 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Letters from friends to FRB re engagement, 1914 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Letters to Clella and others (carbons), 1914-1922 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Letters to Clella (and carbons), 1923-1924 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Clella and children, 1927 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Letterbook, 1927 January-1927 November (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Letters to Clella (carbons), 1927 November-1928 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Letters from Clella and children; miscellaneous household statements, 1927 November-1927 December (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Letters from Clella and children, 1928 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Clella, 1929 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Clella and children, 1941-1949 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Letters to Clella, Undated (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Notes from children, Undated (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Letters re Fred Brown Jr. (birth, death), 1916; 1920 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Letters re Hester Brown's birth, 1918 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Hester C. Brown: Correspondence, academic record, Undated (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with Clara and Frank Argelander, 1951-1966 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Correspondence with Bishop Birney, 1925-1926 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Bishop Birney, 1927 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Correspondence with Bishop Birney, 1928 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence with Bishop Birney, 1929 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Correspondence with Bishop Birney, 1929-1930 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    (With 1953 covering letter from Clella).
  - Correspondence with Frank C. Gale, 1952-1963 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with Evaline Gaw, 1931-1936 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with William R. Johnson, 1916-1965 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Correspondence with John W. B. Lai, 1962-1964 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Letters from former parishioners in China, 1948-1949 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Letters from others, 1920-1937 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Correspondence (family, friends, parishioners), 1960-1961 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Correspondence re ancient Chinese coins, 1952 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Correspondence re church matters, 1916-1930 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Emergency code, 1915 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Christmas/New Years letters, 1934-1957 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Christmas mailing lists, 1953-1958 (Box 3 (4-Correspondence), Folder 34)
- China and the Far East, 1926-1927; 5
  China and the Far East: political and religious conditions in China, Korea, and Japan. Concentration is on the activities of the Nationalist Armies in 1926-1927.
  - The Provinces of China, 1910 (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 35)
  - Capture of Nanchang by Nationalist Armies, 1926-1927 (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 36)
  - Chiang Kai Shik: Speech at Nanchang, 1927 March (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 37)
  - Nationalist Movement, 1927 (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 38)
  - China, Undated (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 39)
    Political conditions; Clippings; translation of "Articles of the Mao-Stalin Pact".
  - Statistics: Non-religious, China, Undated (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 40)
  - Congressional Record, 1919 (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 41)
  - "The World Crisis in the Far East", Undated (Box 3 (5-China and the Far East), Folder 42)
- Kan River District, 1922; 6
  Descriptive material on the Kan River District. Includes a geographical and economic survey of the District, a report on war conditions and the effects on the people, and a study on literacy among church members.
  - Kan River District, Undated (Box 3 (6-Kan River District), Folder 43)
  - "Conditions on the Kan River, Late June and Early July", 1922 (Box 3 (6-Kan River District), Folder 44)
  - "Kan River District: A Study in Literacy among Church Members", 1922 (Box 3 (6-Kan River District), Folder 45)
- Kiangsi Province, 1920-1924; 7
  Descriptive material on the geography and sociology of Kiangsi Province. Papers cover clan customs, superstitions, opium.
  - "Kiangsi Province in China", Undated (Box 3 (7-Kiangsi Province), Folder 46)
  - "Areas and Populations by Districts. Kiangsi Conference", 1922 (Box 3 (7-Kiangsi Province), Folder 47)
  - "Clan Customs in Kiangsi Province", Undated (Box 3 (7-Kiangsi Province), Folder 48)
  - "Superstitions Common in Kiangsi Province", 1920 (Box 3 (7-Kiangsi Province), Folder 49)
  - Kiangsi Province superstitions, Undated (Box 3 (7-Kiangsi Province), Folder 50)
  - "Opium in Kiangsi. Constitution of the Kiangsi Anti-Narcotic Association. Chinese and English Text", 1924 (Box 3 (7-Kiangsi Province), Folder 51)
- Kienchang and Nanchang districts, 1922; 8
  Historical and scientific data.
  - Kienchang District, 1922 (Box 3 (8-Kienchang and Nanchang districts), Folder 52)
  - Nanchang District, Undated (Box 3 (8-Kienchang and Nanchang districts), Folder 53)
  - Nanchang - Scientific data, Undated (Box 3 (8-Kienchang and Nanchang districts), Folder 54)
  - Gale, Francis Clair. "Historical and Traditional Data about Nanchang", Undated (Box 3 (8-Kienchang and Nanchang districts), Folder 55)
- Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang Mission, 1912-1959; 9
  Documents and records concerning the work of the Board of Foreign Missions of the Methodist Episcopal Church in the City of Nanchang, Province of Kiangsi, China (William Nast College and Nanchang General Hospital). Note: Correspondence in Series IV also has information on mission affairs. Oversized items, such as atlases of foreign missions, have been moved to Series XVIII.
  - Methodists in China, Undated (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 56)
  - "Communist Persecution of Churches in Red China and Northern Korea", 1959 (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 57)
  - "1920-1921 Evangelistic Campaign Hymns: Kiukiang & Nanchang", Undated (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 58)
  - Power of Attorney (for Nanchang Mission), 1915 (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 59)
  - Business matters, 1912; 1918 (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 60)
    Administrative Rules Adopted by the Finance Committee of the Kiangsi Mission... 1918.
  - Contracts and insurance policies, Undated (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 61)
  - Inventories of household furnishings, personal property, Undated (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 62)
  - Orders, bills, Undated (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 63)
  - Mission affairs, 1927 (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 64a)
  - "Sermons and other Devotional and Meditational Material", 1927-1928 (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 64b)
  - Kuling Estate, 1936 (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 65)
  - The Kwanyuenmen Project, 1923 (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 66)
  - Nanchang General Hospital: Blueprints, song, Undated (Box 3 (9-Methodist Episcopal Church in China: the Nanchang ), Folder 67)
- Teaching at the Nanchang Mission, 1920s; 10
  FRB's teaching activities at the mission; religious instruction. Includes policy statements from the Methodist Church; regulations of the Nationalist government; FRB's master's thesis; his report on religious education; educational conference reports, lesson plans, class schedules. Most of the material is from the 1920s.
  - International Sunday School Lesson Committee. "Statement of a Theory of Curriculum", 1923 (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 68)
  - Religious Education of the Methodist Episcopal Church, Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 69)
  - "Educational Regulations of the Nationalist Government", 1928 (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 70)
  - "A Curriculum for Methodist Episcopal Sunday Schools in the Central China Area". (Master's thesis), 1925 (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 71)
  - "Religious Education in Nanchang Academy", 1928; carbon of typescript (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 72)
  - "Christian Education in Nanchang", from Educational Review, Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 73)
  - Conference on Christian Education (Educational Review October 1931; Index 1931), Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 74)
  - Kuling Summer School of Religious Education, 1929 (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 75)
  - Class schedules, Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 76)
  - Plans for religious studies, Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 77)
  - Class notes on Old Testament theology, 1924-1925 (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 78)
  - Dramatic exercises, Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 79)
    "A Christmas Carol"; "The Star of Bethlehem"; "Jonah"; "Domestic Tranquility or, Life as She Is Lived in the Orient".
  - "The Story of Jonah in dramatic forrp", Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 80)
  - "Jesus' Exclamation Points", Undated (Box 3 (10-Teaching at the Nanchang Mission), Folder 81)
- University of Amoy, 1931; Undated; 11